<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-11-05T13:00:11-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Weifan Zhou</title><subtitle>Hi :D</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Today</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/random/thoughts/2024/11/04/Historic_Turning_Point.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Today" /><published>2024-11-04T23:30:10-06:00</published><updated>2024-11-04T23:30:10-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/random/thoughts/2024/11/04/Historic_Turning_Point</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/random/thoughts/2024/11/04/Historic_Turning_Point.html"><![CDATA[<p>I am an international student who cannot vote. The only reason I wrote this article is that I feel today is a turning point in history, and I hope it might be helpful for any historians 1,000 years from now. (Well, I’m just joking.)</p>

<p>We know November 5 is the voting date in the United States. Previously, the only way I observed the vote was through television or the internet because I wasn’t in the United States four years ago. Observing the voting day on campus for the first time was more engaging than I expected.</p>

<p>In the morning, the violinist I accompany contacted me to reschedule our rehearsal because they needed to find time to vote. I agreed. Then, when I opened social media, I saw many friends posting messages encouraging people to vote. They were spreading information about how to vote and emphasizing the importance of voting rights. I’m not sure what it was like in previous years, but I can see strong participation from U.S. Gen Z in the 2024 presidential election.</p>

<p>This year, I’ve noticed many changes, such as Joseph Biden stepping down, attacks on Trump, the involvement of social media and tech companies, concerns about potential conflicts after this year’s election, the ongoing and potential wars, and the increasing polarization of ideologies. Diversity and localization seem to be clashing in significant ways.</p>

<p>I believe that no matter who is elected, this election is a historic turning point. People want to "correct" the course of history, but they are still part of a larger historical trend.</p>

<p>Especially under a society that is not quite transparent.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Random" /><category term="Thoughts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am an international student who cannot vote. The only reason I wrote this article is that I feel today is a turning point in history, and I hope it might be helpful for any historians 1,000 years from now. (Well, I’m just joking.)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Anxiety</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/random/thoughts/2024/10/22/Anxiety.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Anxiety" /><published>2024-10-22T00:53:10-05:00</published><updated>2024-10-22T00:53:10-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/random/thoughts/2024/10/22/Anxiety</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/random/thoughts/2024/10/22/Anxiety.html"><![CDATA[<p>Many things happened in the last two months, including swithing my major, suffering from homework attack, and overcoming flu. I was so anxious, and many days I refuse to sleep early. One reason is I couldn’t, because I wasn’t that tired, and another reason is, did I dare to?</p>

<p>I felt so much burden and desperate when seeing deadlines throwing to me. Whenever I finish something and would like to take a rest, on the homework system, new task reminder poped up. I was like a running hamster, or a person who paid for high interest rate and could never wait for the day to pay off the debt. To sleep or not to sleep, both will make me guilty, and no matter which option I chose, when I sleep or woke up, I was surrounded by fear.</p>

<p>Yesterday, with the fear of not graduating on time, the desire of “finish my GIS homework early”, the struggle of ansering my students’ qustion on time, but I was also tired. I was lost. I wanted to solve those problems so much, and I spend the whole night to find potential winter and summer session, considering which course to take the next 3 semesters, but with everying tangled in my mind, I felt like a drunkard.</p>

<p>Some of you might say, that, you are too greedy, and it was impossible to do so much things in a short period of time. But using an analogy, is it possible for a poor guy to buy a house instead of rent a house, and have debt for such a long time? Even if in the long term it saves money, is it possible for a person to make utilitarian decision under a “limited” condition?</p>

<p>Many children in the early 21st century have higher opportunity cost than their parents, including risks of college debt, economy recession, and shrinked job opportunities. Many of us were not encouraged to slow down, which will also reach the goal of learning without sacrificing physical and mental health. But we 15-20s are losing courage, being told only one or two types of life, burning our energies we are supposed to use in our 30s, and got sick.</p>

<p>I could no longer keep awake when it was 5 or 6 o’clock, and I fell asleep. When I woke up by alarm, slept again, and checked the time again, it was already 10:50. I missed my classes, and was going to miss another one.</p>

<p>I wrote an email to apologize to my professor, and then chose to skip the class.</p>

<p>I walked on the trail. It was such a nice day, with bight sunlight, and all leaves just turn red (which seemed all of a sudden). Walking on the road, with chrunchy leaves on the pavement, I was surrounded by tall, bright red and orange, which was totally different from any pictures or telivisions. It was like heavan.</p>

<p>I returned the trash computer, and back to the classroom, and took a photo of the board in within the last 10 minutes of the class.</p>

<p>Actually, it wasn’t much loss.</p>

<p>For such a long time in college, I seemed to do what I “supposed” to do, but I have never asked, “what do you really want to do”, and “people don’t need to have the same life”.</p>

<p>Stop pushing us.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Random" /><category term="Thoughts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Many things happened in the last two months, including swithing my major, suffering from homework attack, and overcoming flu. I was so anxious, and many days I refuse to sleep early. One reason is I couldn’t, because I wasn’t that tired, and another reason is, did I dare to?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">(未完成的）虚构故事：停电</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/random/stories/2024/07/24/%E4%BA%BA%E5%B7%A5%E6%99%BA%E8%83%BD%E7%BA%AA%E5%85%83.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="(未完成的）虚构故事：停电" /><published>2024-07-24T00:53:10-05:00</published><updated>2024-07-24T00:53:10-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/random/stories/2024/07/24/%E4%BA%BA%E5%B7%A5%E6%99%BA%E8%83%BD%E7%BA%AA%E5%85%83</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/random/stories/2024/07/24/%E4%BA%BA%E5%B7%A5%E6%99%BA%E8%83%BD%E7%BA%AA%E5%85%83.html"><![CDATA[<p>由于战乱、选举舞弊、资金不透明等等，各国政府逐渐失去了公信力。世界开始了长达30年左右的无政府时期，小事由宗族、社区解决，大事由互联网辩论。与此同时，因为越来越多人使用新科技，在“要不要取消现金”“要不要让小学教师下岗”等事情上，不同宗族与社区之间争吵不休。于是在某年三月，地球上出现了一个叫做“地球委员会”的组织，负责评估一项新发明对于人类生活方式的影响，以及人类是否应该保留旧的生活方式。</p>

<p>地球委员会于近期通过了一项决议。鉴于越来越多民众使用自动驾驶，而网络论坛上一直充斥着“人工驾驶会导致混乱”一说，地球委员会以微弱优势通过了“淘汰人工驾驶”的决议，在北印度某邦进行试点。起先这项决议没有引起太大讨论，毕竟司机十年前早就下岗转行，并且不少人由于游行，被其他宗族的人关进私人监狱，或者他们的社交媒体早就被封号。但是决议通过后半年，一则新闻引起了轩然大波：</p>

<p><blockquote>地球委员会某位议员因为上班要迟到，为了节省时间，汽车算法决定一路向前冲。但是议员的汽车与平民的汽车算法发生冲突。由于算法没有完备的解决冲突机制，根据“最大化原则”，议员的工作被认为“更重要”，他的汽车撞死了平民。</blockquote></p>

<p>事实上，此事发生前，就有一些因为算法导致的事情发生，例如自动驾驶救护车撞伤平民，但是科技公司给受害者家属付了高额的封口费，此事也不了了之。业内人士知道，他们公司的伦理专家早就针对类似的事情发出过警告，但是管理层为了稳住股价，便没有公开算法相关的风险。</p>

<p>地球委员会的涉事议员被暂停公职，而算法工程师也突然“失踪”。地球委员会也叫停了“普及自动化驾驶”的进程。此事或许应该告一段落，但是这件新闻也导致阴谋论开始发酵。“科技公司要钱不要命”“官商勾结”“地球委员会为了一己私利操纵科技走向”充斥于各大头版。</p>

<p>与此同时，一位扎波罗热的技术兵，刚从没人管的边境口岸出逃，身上也没有值钱的东西，在长途跋涉后晕倒在了波罗的海边上。醒来后，他发现自己躺在一个无人的电竞房里。突然，电脑打开了，跳出一份信件：</p>

<p><blockquote><p>地球人每日于地面打仗，甚至已经封锁了核电站与火山口。这些举措已经影响到了我们的出行。我们将资助您的生活物资，请您想办法让他们消停一阵子。不胜感激。</p>
<p>我们之所以找您，是因为只有地球人才了解地球人。</p>
<p style="text-align:right;">--地心人</p>
</blockquote></p>

<p>扎波罗热人咬咬牙。反正自己也是被抓壮丁的大学生，被地球上的军阀发现，也要被遣送回去。他回复道：</p>

<p><blockquote>如果您有能力，请黑掉并暂停他们的电力设施，以暂停他们的自动导弹及无人机系统。不胜感激。</blockquote><p>

<p>几个小时后，地球大部分地区突然灯光熄灭，大部分设备陷入黑屏。</p>

---------

<em>（不想续写。）</em>
</p></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Random" /><category term="Stories" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[由于战乱、选举舞弊、资金不透明等等，各国政府逐渐失去了公信力。世界开始了长达30年左右的无政府时期，小事由宗族、社区解决，大事由互联网辩论。与此同时，因为越来越多人使用新科技，在“要不要取消现金”“要不要让小学教师下岗”等事情上，不同宗族与社区之间争吵不休。于是在某年三月，地球上出现了一个叫做“地球委员会”的组织，负责评估一项新发明对于人类生活方式的影响，以及人类是否应该保留旧的生活方式。]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Moral and Ethical Concern of Autonomous Weapons</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/random/thoughts/2024/05/08/Ethics_of_Autonomous_Weapons.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Moral and Ethical Concern of Autonomous Weapons" /><published>2024-05-08T23:32:10-05:00</published><updated>2024-05-08T23:32:10-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/random/thoughts/2024/05/08/Ethics_of_Autonomous_Weapons</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/random/thoughts/2024/05/08/Ethics_of_Autonomous_Weapons.html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Note: This is an assignment from my Cybertechnology Ethics (PHIL 222) class from Illinois Wesleyan University. The essay was finished in April 30, 2024.</em></p>

<hr />

<p>In modern wars such as the Ukraine War, some advanced technologies like drones are used for killing enemies without soldiers going to the battlefield. Those drones have used artificial intelligence for targeting people, which raised people's concern about whether it is too cruel to use  autonomous weapons in wars. In this paper, I am going to argue that developing autonomous weapons is morally wrong because it puts civilians under threats. To reach this goal, I am going to show the definition of autonomous weapons systems, illustrate ethical concerns of wars and such weapons, and discuss potential objections.</p>
<p>Before discussing potential issues of autonomous weapons, it is essential to define what the autonomous weapons system is. Asaro provides the definition of autonomous weapons system based on the International Committee of the Red Cross, that “an autonomous weapon system is any system that automates the critical functions of targeting and engaging a weapon. This means that the targeting and use of force must be automated for the system to be considered an autonomous weapon" (213). This definition highlights the key characteristic of autonomous weapons: the complete absence of human intervention in the critical functions of targeting and engaging targets. It distinctly separates autonomous weapons from traditional or semi-autonomous systems such as drones, which still require human control for critical decision-making tasks like selecting and confirming targets. 
The primary moral concern of autonomous weapons is that without human control, such weapons can harm civilians more easily. Asaro mentioned that “autonomous weapons could be easily designed, altered, or manipulated to purposely harm civilians… Despots and tyrants might turn such weapons against their own people or apply them to genocidal ends, or terrorists might use them to attack civilians'' (215). When using traditional weapons, which are more complicated to control, the decision makers (such as the president) cannot conduct attacks themselves but give this power to the army; it usually takes a long to give orders layer by layer to military forces, who can delay or even refuse to attack. But using autonomous weapons, which only require setting a target, the decision makers can operate weapons themselves immediately. This issue raises significant ethical demands not only concerning the autonomous weapons themselves but also regarding the morality of their operators. However, it is almost impossible to ensure every user of those weapons has such a high moral quality. Consider a scenario where an unethical individual owns such a weapon; even without engaging in large-scale warfare, they could use it to carry out targeted assassinations against someone they hate. The danger is compounded by the fact that these owners do not need military expertise or to manually select targets; the weapon can autonomously execute lethal actions at any time without direct human oversight.</p>
<p>Another concern of autonomous weapons is that if they are hacked, civilians and infrastructures may be attacked even if autonomous weapons do not plan to target civilians. Since autonomous weapons are using computer technologies, relying on algorithms and input information (such as location and facial images), if GPS system is interrupted or if the database is polluted during a cyberattack, an autonomous weapon may lose its accuracy in determining targets, but instead open fire to some places such as residential zones. Asaro listed a possibility, that “one could do this by attacking its sensors or simply manipulating what those sensors capture… These sensors respond to signals from GPS satellites in space and compute their location from the signals of multiple satellites” (221). The misleading target can lead to unexpected casualties in residential areas and damage in buildings, which leads to morality concern.</p>
<p>Some may still be optimistic about the development of autonomous weapons systems because if those weapons become too powerful, like nuclear bombs, people may stop using them, which can prevent wars and casualties. After World War II, when two autonomous bombs killed massive civilians in Japan, there was no more huge worldwide war because any country with nuclear bombs can just destroy their enemies easily. In some perspectives, the world becomes more cautious about wars, for instance, during Prague Spring, when the Soviet Union invaded Czechoslovakia, western allies such as UK and US did not support Czechoslovakia because the western world is afraid to upgrade conflicts into world war again. Instead, most of the hot wars became economic sanctions, cyberattack, arms race, space race, etc, which significantly reduced casualties. Similarly, there are some ideas of a scenario when autonomous weapons become stronger, causing huge casualties once or twice like nuclear bombs, and then people realize they should not use autonomous weapons anymore because it is too powerful. This claim argues that when autonomous weapons become as powerful as nuclear weapons, people no longer dare to use those weapons or initiate wars, and eventually those advanced autonomous weapons bring peace and become beneficial. More civilians can survive due to the reduction of hot wars.</p>
<p>My response to this objection is, the condition of peace is based on defense systems not developed as quickly as weapons. One of the reasons that nuclear weapons are called powerful is that they can destroy almost any physical defense system, so that no one can avoid death. However, what if there is a new defense system that can provide a “shell” to the city and prevent citizens being killed by nuclear weapons? Think about this scenario: assume there are two countries who do not like each other, having both this new defense system and nuclear weapons. One day both of them planned to declare a war, and since both of them know each of them have a new defense system that can potentially prevent civilians being killed, they will use nuclear weapons to bomb each other without concern. They may assume that those nuclear weapons are not as threatful as in the past because each of them have a defense system to keep them safer, and thus they will resume wars and nuclear weapons again. However, there may be some accidents: what if the defense system does not work, or what if it is hacked, or because the defense system is so expensive that some regions are not protected under the defense system? All those possibilities can cause more casualties than traditional hot wars. Similarly, if there is a defense system for autonomous weapons that many countries have, when people restart autonomous weapon attacks against each other because all of them have the defense system, short peace will end, and in the worst case, there may be more casualties because people no longer keep alert with the harm of autonomous weapons systems, nor will they rethink the risk of the defense system not working. Thus, in the long run, autonomous weapons cannot decrease, or will even lead to more civilian deaths.</p>

<p>In conclusion, I think that developing autonomous weapons systems is unethical, especially for civilians because any immoral individuals who control the weapon, any hackers, or potential defense systems can put citizens under injury or death. In my perspective, rather than developing more powerful weapons, it is more important for people to realize the potential harm of them, no matter if they are powerful or not. </p>

<hr />

<h4 id="work-cited">Work Cited</h4>
<p>Asaro, “Autonomous Weapons and the Ethics of Artificial Intelligence.”</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Random" /><category term="Thoughts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Note: This is an assignment from my Cybertechnology Ethics (PHIL 222) class from Illinois Wesleyan University. The essay was finished in April 30, 2024.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reflection on Flaws of my CS377 British Car Accident Project</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/project/reflection/2024/02/10/Project_reflection.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reflection on Flaws of my CS377 British Car Accident Project" /><published>2024-02-10T23:53:10-06:00</published><updated>2024-02-10T23:53:10-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/project/reflection/2024/02/10/Project_reflection</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/project/reflection/2024/02/10/Project_reflection.html"><![CDATA[<p>Last semester, I wanted to challenge myself a little bit when choosing the final project topic for my Applied Data Analysis class (you can view that on my GitHub). However, there were many flaws in the outcome, such as poor ROCs, ignoring seasons, no maps, and too many records being wiped out, etc., making the prediction less accurate.</p>

<p>Later, I realized that car accident datasets were spatial data, which was full of small disjuncts. Notice that car accidents can only happen on roads, which means that some places, like residential zones, can never be potential sites for highway car crashes.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, roads are spaced apart, from district to district. There is a distance between roads, and thus, rather than a linear relationship, the association between car accidents and longitude / latitude may follow a 'clock cycle' pattern. Without considering their actual locations, predictions of accident severity can be problematic.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Project" /><category term="Reflection" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last semester, I wanted to challenge myself a little bit when choosing the final project topic for my Applied Data Analysis class (you can view that on my GitHub). However, there were many flaws in the outcome, such as poor ROCs, ignoring seasons, no maps, and too many records being wiped out, etc., making the prediction less accurate.]]></summary></entry></feed>