<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-11-05T17:46:23-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Weifan Zhou</title><subtitle>Hi :D</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Today</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/random/thoughts/2024/11/04/Historic_Turning_Point.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Today" /><published>2024-11-04T23:30:10-06:00</published><updated>2024-11-04T23:30:10-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/random/thoughts/2024/11/04/Historic_Turning_Point</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/random/thoughts/2024/11/04/Historic_Turning_Point.html"><![CDATA[<p>I am an international student who cannot vote. The only reason I wrote this article is that I feel today is a turning point in history, and I hope it might be helpful for any historians 1,000 years from now. (Well, I’m just joking.)</p>

<p>We know November 5 is the voting date in the United States. Previously, the only way I observed the vote was through television or the internet because I wasn’t in the United States four years ago. Observing the voting day on campus for the first time was more engaging than I expected.</p>

<p>In the morning, the violinist I accompany contacted me to reschedule our rehearsal because they needed to find time to vote. I agreed. Then, when I opened social media, I saw many friends posting messages encouraging people to vote. They were spreading information about how to vote and emphasizing the importance of voting rights. I’m not sure what it was like in previous years, but I can see strong participation from U.S. Gen Z in the 2024 presidential election.</p>

<p>This year, I’ve noticed many changes, such as Joseph Biden stepping down, attacks on Trump, the involvement of social media and tech companies, concerns about potential conflicts after this year’s election, the ongoing and potential wars, and the increasing polarization of ideologies. Diversity and localization seem to be clashing in significant ways.</p>

<p>I believe that no matter who is elected, this election is a historic turning point. People want to "correct" the course of history, but they are still part of a larger historical trend.</p>

<p>Especially under a society that is not quite transparent.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Random" /><category term="Thoughts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am an international student who cannot vote. The only reason I wrote this article is that I feel today is a turning point in history, and I hope it might be helpful for any historians 1,000 years from now. (Well, I’m just joking.)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Anxiety</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/random/thoughts/2024/10/22/Anxiety.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Anxiety" /><published>2024-10-22T00:53:10-05:00</published><updated>2024-10-22T00:53:10-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/random/thoughts/2024/10/22/Anxiety</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/random/thoughts/2024/10/22/Anxiety.html"><![CDATA[<p>Many things happened in the last two months, including swithing my major, suffering from homework attack, and overcoming flu. I was so anxious, and many days I refuse to sleep early. One reason is I couldn’t, because I wasn’t that tired, and another reason is, did I dare to?</p>

<p>I felt so much burden and desperate when seeing deadlines throwing to me. Whenever I finish something and would like to take a rest, on the homework system, new task reminder poped up. I was like a running hamster, or a person who paid for high interest rate and could never wait for the day to pay off the debt. To sleep or not to sleep, both will make me guilty, and no matter which option I chose, when I sleep or woke up, I was surrounded by fear.</p>

<p>Yesterday, with the fear of not graduating on time, the desire of “finish my GIS homework early”, the struggle of ansering my students’ qustion on time, but I was also tired. I was lost. I wanted to solve those problems so much, and I spend the whole night to find potential winter and summer session, considering which course to take the next 3 semesters, but with everying tangled in my mind, I felt like a drunkard.</p>

<p>Some of you might say, that, you are too greedy, and it was impossible to do so much things in a short period of time. But using an analogy, is it possible for a poor guy to buy a house instead of rent a house, and have debt for such a long time? Even if in the long term it saves money, is it possible for a person to make utilitarian decision under a “limited” condition?</p>

<p>Many children in the early 21st century have higher opportunity cost than their parents, including risks of college debt, economy recession, and shrinked job opportunities. Many of us were not encouraged to slow down, which will also reach the goal of learning without sacrificing physical and mental health. But we 15-20s are losing courage, being told only one or two types of life, burning our energies we are supposed to use in our 30s, and got sick.</p>

<p>I could no longer keep awake when it was 5 or 6 o’clock, and I fell asleep. When I woke up by alarm, slept again, and checked the time again, it was already 10:50. I missed my classes, and was going to miss another one.</p>

<p>I wrote an email to apologize to my professor, and then chose to skip the class.</p>

<p>I walked on the trail. It was such a nice day, with bight sunlight, and all leaves just turn red (which seemed all of a sudden). Walking on the road, with chrunchy leaves on the pavement, I was surrounded by tall, bright red and orange, which was totally different from any pictures or telivisions. It was like heavan.</p>

<p>I returned the trash computer, and back to the classroom, and took a photo of the board in within the last 10 minutes of the class.</p>

<p>Actually, it wasn’t much loss.</p>

<p>For such a long time in college, I seemed to do what I “supposed” to do, but I have never asked, “what do you really want to do”, and “people don’t need to have the same life”.</p>

<p>Stop pushing us.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Random" /><category term="Thoughts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Many things happened in the last two months, including swithing my major, suffering from homework attack, and overcoming flu. I was so anxious, and many days I refuse to sleep early. One reason is I couldn’t, because I wasn’t that tired, and another reason is, did I dare to?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">关于ADHD</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/collection/2024/07/24/adhd.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="关于ADHD" /><published>2024-07-24T00:53:10-05:00</published><updated>2024-07-24T00:53:10-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/collection/2024/07/24/adhd</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/collection/2024/07/24/adhd.html"><![CDATA[<p>纽约时报曾于2013年刊登过一篇文章：<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2013/10/20/magazine/the-not-so-hidden-cause-behind-the-adhd-epidemic.html"> The Not-So-Hidden Cause Behind the A.D.H.D. Epidemic </a> 。它探讨了美国ADHD诊断率提高的背后因素之一。<a href="https://cn.nytimes.com/education/20131105/t05adhd/">中文版</a>也可以找到（虽然它的标题翻译有问题）。</p>

<p>这篇文章比较了2007年北卡州与加州4-17岁孩子的ADHD确诊率，发现前者（15.6%）的诊断率为后者（6.2%）的两倍。该差异的巨大因素之一是“No Child Left Behind Act"法案。</p>

<blockquote>由乔治·布什(George W. Bush)签署的“有教无类法案”(No Child Left Behind Act)是第一项将学校的财政拨款与标准化考试成绩联系在一起的联邦法案。但是在过去30年中，各州都在缓慢推行类似的政策。北卡罗来纳州是首批引进这种项目的州之一；而加州是最末一批中的一员。这些法律的施行与注意力缺陷多动障碍确诊率之间的关联在地域范围内也是成立的。当欣肖把这些学校政策与注意力缺陷多动障碍的发生率进行比对时，他发现当一个州通过视标准化考试得分对学校进行赏罚的法律时，不久之后该州的注意力缺陷多动障碍诊断就会上升。在全美国范围内，在“有教无类法案”颁布后的前四年，注意力缺陷多动障碍诊断率增长了22%。</blockquote>

<p>这篇文章中也提到了美国相比于欧洲更高的ADHD诊断率，其因素之一是美国使用不一样的诊断手册。</p>

<p>诊断后的下一步是什么？用药。但是是否有过度诊断、滥用药物的可能性？药物的副作用，即使现在没有被证实，但长期来看呢？试验基本用在动物身上，而动物的生命周期相比人类更短，无法进行长达几十年的试验，有些后遗症无法发现。</p>

<p>我在网上也看到了一些有意思的帖子，例如：“对于坐不住或学不进去的孩子，诊断成ADHD喂药，实则是方便了学校和家长”，又例如“这是一项学校的懒政”。</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Collection" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[纽约时报曾于2013年刊登过一篇文章： The Not-So-Hidden Cause Behind the A.D.H.D. Epidemic 。它探讨了美国ADHD诊断率提高的背后因素之一。中文版也可以找到（虽然它的标题翻译有问题）。]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">(未完成的）虚构故事：停电</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/random/stories/2024/07/24/%E4%BA%BA%E5%B7%A5%E6%99%BA%E8%83%BD%E7%BA%AA%E5%85%83.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="(未完成的）虚构故事：停电" /><published>2024-07-24T00:53:10-05:00</published><updated>2024-07-24T00:53:10-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/random/stories/2024/07/24/%E4%BA%BA%E5%B7%A5%E6%99%BA%E8%83%BD%E7%BA%AA%E5%85%83</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/random/stories/2024/07/24/%E4%BA%BA%E5%B7%A5%E6%99%BA%E8%83%BD%E7%BA%AA%E5%85%83.html"><![CDATA[<p>由于战乱、选举舞弊、资金不透明等等，各国政府逐渐失去了公信力。世界开始了长达30年左右的无政府时期，小事由宗族、社区解决，大事由互联网辩论。与此同时，因为越来越多人使用新科技，在“要不要取消现金”“要不要让小学教师下岗”等事情上，不同宗族与社区之间争吵不休。于是在某年三月，地球上出现了一个叫做“地球委员会”的组织，负责评估一项新发明对于人类生活方式的影响，以及人类是否应该保留旧的生活方式。</p>

<p>地球委员会于近期通过了一项决议。鉴于越来越多民众使用自动驾驶，而网络论坛上一直充斥着“人工驾驶会导致混乱”一说，地球委员会以微弱优势通过了“淘汰人工驾驶”的决议，在北印度某邦进行试点。起先这项决议没有引起太大讨论，毕竟司机十年前早就下岗转行，并且不少人由于游行，被其他宗族的人关进私人监狱，或者他们的社交媒体早就被封号。但是决议通过后半年，一则新闻引起了轩然大波：</p>

<p><blockquote>地球委员会某位议员因为上班要迟到，为了节省时间，汽车算法决定一路向前冲。但是议员的汽车与平民的汽车算法发生冲突。由于算法没有完备的解决冲突机制，根据“最大化原则”，议员的工作被认为“更重要”，他的汽车撞死了平民。</blockquote></p>

<p>事实上，此事发生前，就有一些因为算法导致的事情发生，例如自动驾驶救护车撞伤平民，但是科技公司给受害者家属付了高额的封口费，此事也不了了之。业内人士知道，他们公司的伦理专家早就针对类似的事情发出过警告，但是管理层为了稳住股价，便没有公开算法相关的风险。</p>

<p>地球委员会的涉事议员被暂停公职，而算法工程师也突然“失踪”。地球委员会也叫停了“普及自动化驾驶”的进程。此事或许应该告一段落，但是这件新闻也导致阴谋论开始发酵。“科技公司要钱不要命”“官商勾结”“地球委员会为了一己私利操纵科技走向”充斥于各大头版。</p>

<p>与此同时，一位扎波罗热的技术兵，刚从没人管的边境口岸出逃，身上也没有值钱的东西，在长途跋涉后晕倒在了波罗的海边上。醒来后，他发现自己躺在一个无人的电竞房里。突然，电脑打开了，跳出一份信件：</p>

<p><blockquote><p>地球人每日于地面打仗，甚至已经封锁了核电站与火山口。这些举措已经影响到了我们的出行。我们将资助您的生活物资，请您想办法让他们消停一阵子。不胜感激。</p>
<p>我们之所以找您，是因为只有地球人才了解地球人。</p>
<p style="text-align:right;">--地心人</p>
</blockquote></p>

<p>扎波罗热人咬咬牙。反正自己也是被抓壮丁的大学生，被地球上的军阀发现，也要被遣送回去。他回复道：</p>

<p><blockquote>如果您有能力，请黑掉并暂停他们的电力设施，以暂停他们的自动导弹及无人机系统。不胜感激。</blockquote><p>

<p>几个小时后，地球大部分地区突然灯光熄灭，大部分设备陷入黑屏。</p>

---------

<em>（不想续写。）</em>
</p></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Random" /><category term="Stories" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[由于战乱、选举舞弊、资金不透明等等，各国政府逐渐失去了公信力。世界开始了长达30年左右的无政府时期，小事由宗族、社区解决，大事由互联网辩论。与此同时，因为越来越多人使用新科技，在“要不要取消现金”“要不要让小学教师下岗”等事情上，不同宗族与社区之间争吵不休。于是在某年三月，地球上出现了一个叫做“地球委员会”的组织，负责评估一项新发明对于人类生活方式的影响，以及人类是否应该保留旧的生活方式。]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Moral and Ethical Concern of Autonomous Weapons</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/random/thoughts/2024/05/08/Ethics_of_Autonomous_Weapons.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Moral and Ethical Concern of Autonomous Weapons" /><published>2024-05-08T23:32:10-05:00</published><updated>2024-05-08T23:32:10-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/random/thoughts/2024/05/08/Ethics_of_Autonomous_Weapons</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/random/thoughts/2024/05/08/Ethics_of_Autonomous_Weapons.html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Note: This is an assignment from my Cybertechnology Ethics (PHIL 222) class from Illinois Wesleyan University. The essay was finished in April 30, 2024.</em></p>

<hr />

<p>In modern wars such as the Ukraine War, some advanced technologies like drones are used for killing enemies without soldiers going to the battlefield. Those drones have used artificial intelligence for targeting people, which raised people's concern about whether it is too cruel to use  autonomous weapons in wars. In this paper, I am going to argue that developing autonomous weapons is morally wrong because it puts civilians under threats. To reach this goal, I am going to show the definition of autonomous weapons systems, illustrate ethical concerns of wars and such weapons, and discuss potential objections.</p>
<p>Before discussing potential issues of autonomous weapons, it is essential to define what the autonomous weapons system is. Asaro provides the definition of autonomous weapons system based on the International Committee of the Red Cross, that “an autonomous weapon system is any system that automates the critical functions of targeting and engaging a weapon. This means that the targeting and use of force must be automated for the system to be considered an autonomous weapon" (213). This definition highlights the key characteristic of autonomous weapons: the complete absence of human intervention in the critical functions of targeting and engaging targets. It distinctly separates autonomous weapons from traditional or semi-autonomous systems such as drones, which still require human control for critical decision-making tasks like selecting and confirming targets. 
The primary moral concern of autonomous weapons is that without human control, such weapons can harm civilians more easily. Asaro mentioned that “autonomous weapons could be easily designed, altered, or manipulated to purposely harm civilians… Despots and tyrants might turn such weapons against their own people or apply them to genocidal ends, or terrorists might use them to attack civilians'' (215). When using traditional weapons, which are more complicated to control, the decision makers (such as the president) cannot conduct attacks themselves but give this power to the army; it usually takes a long to give orders layer by layer to military forces, who can delay or even refuse to attack. But using autonomous weapons, which only require setting a target, the decision makers can operate weapons themselves immediately. This issue raises significant ethical demands not only concerning the autonomous weapons themselves but also regarding the morality of their operators. However, it is almost impossible to ensure every user of those weapons has such a high moral quality. Consider a scenario where an unethical individual owns such a weapon; even without engaging in large-scale warfare, they could use it to carry out targeted assassinations against someone they hate. The danger is compounded by the fact that these owners do not need military expertise or to manually select targets; the weapon can autonomously execute lethal actions at any time without direct human oversight.</p>
<p>Another concern of autonomous weapons is that if they are hacked, civilians and infrastructures may be attacked even if autonomous weapons do not plan to target civilians. Since autonomous weapons are using computer technologies, relying on algorithms and input information (such as location and facial images), if GPS system is interrupted or if the database is polluted during a cyberattack, an autonomous weapon may lose its accuracy in determining targets, but instead open fire to some places such as residential zones. Asaro listed a possibility, that “one could do this by attacking its sensors or simply manipulating what those sensors capture… These sensors respond to signals from GPS satellites in space and compute their location from the signals of multiple satellites” (221). The misleading target can lead to unexpected casualties in residential areas and damage in buildings, which leads to morality concern.</p>
<p>Some may still be optimistic about the development of autonomous weapons systems because if those weapons become too powerful, like nuclear bombs, people may stop using them, which can prevent wars and casualties. After World War II, when two autonomous bombs killed massive civilians in Japan, there was no more huge worldwide war because any country with nuclear bombs can just destroy their enemies easily. In some perspectives, the world becomes more cautious about wars, for instance, during Prague Spring, when the Soviet Union invaded Czechoslovakia, western allies such as UK and US did not support Czechoslovakia because the western world is afraid to upgrade conflicts into world war again. Instead, most of the hot wars became economic sanctions, cyberattack, arms race, space race, etc, which significantly reduced casualties. Similarly, there are some ideas of a scenario when autonomous weapons become stronger, causing huge casualties once or twice like nuclear bombs, and then people realize they should not use autonomous weapons anymore because it is too powerful. This claim argues that when autonomous weapons become as powerful as nuclear weapons, people no longer dare to use those weapons or initiate wars, and eventually those advanced autonomous weapons bring peace and become beneficial. More civilians can survive due to the reduction of hot wars.</p>
<p>My response to this objection is, the condition of peace is based on defense systems not developed as quickly as weapons. One of the reasons that nuclear weapons are called powerful is that they can destroy almost any physical defense system, so that no one can avoid death. However, what if there is a new defense system that can provide a “shell” to the city and prevent citizens being killed by nuclear weapons? Think about this scenario: assume there are two countries who do not like each other, having both this new defense system and nuclear weapons. One day both of them planned to declare a war, and since both of them know each of them have a new defense system that can potentially prevent civilians being killed, they will use nuclear weapons to bomb each other without concern. They may assume that those nuclear weapons are not as threatful as in the past because each of them have a defense system to keep them safer, and thus they will resume wars and nuclear weapons again. However, there may be some accidents: what if the defense system does not work, or what if it is hacked, or because the defense system is so expensive that some regions are not protected under the defense system? All those possibilities can cause more casualties than traditional hot wars. Similarly, if there is a defense system for autonomous weapons that many countries have, when people restart autonomous weapon attacks against each other because all of them have the defense system, short peace will end, and in the worst case, there may be more casualties because people no longer keep alert with the harm of autonomous weapons systems, nor will they rethink the risk of the defense system not working. Thus, in the long run, autonomous weapons cannot decrease, or will even lead to more civilian deaths.</p>

<p>In conclusion, I think that developing autonomous weapons systems is unethical, especially for civilians because any immoral individuals who control the weapon, any hackers, or potential defense systems can put citizens under injury or death. In my perspective, rather than developing more powerful weapons, it is more important for people to realize the potential harm of them, no matter if they are powerful or not. </p>

<hr />

<h4 id="work-cited">Work Cited</h4>
<p>Asaro, “Autonomous Weapons and the Ethics of Artificial Intelligence.”</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Random" /><category term="Thoughts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Note: This is an assignment from my Cybertechnology Ethics (PHIL 222) class from Illinois Wesleyan University. The essay was finished in April 30, 2024.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reflection on Flaws of my CS377 British Car Accident Project</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/project/reflection/2024/02/10/Project_reflection.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reflection on Flaws of my CS377 British Car Accident Project" /><published>2024-02-10T23:53:10-06:00</published><updated>2024-02-10T23:53:10-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/project/reflection/2024/02/10/Project_reflection</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/project/reflection/2024/02/10/Project_reflection.html"><![CDATA[<p>Last semester, I wanted to challenge myself a little bit when choosing the final project topic for my Applied Data Analysis class (you can view that on my GitHub). However, there were many flaws in the outcome, such as poor ROCs, ignoring seasons, no maps, and too many records being wiped out, etc., making the prediction less accurate.</p>

<p>Later, I realized that car accident datasets were spatial data, which was full of small disjuncts. Notice that car accidents can only happen on roads, which means that some places, like residential zones, can never be potential sites for highway car crashes.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, roads are spaced apart, from district to district. There is a distance between roads, and thus, rather than a linear relationship, the association between car accidents and longitude / latitude may follow a 'clock cycle' pattern. Without considering their actual locations, predictions of accident severity can be problematic.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Project" /><category term="Reflection" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last semester, I wanted to challenge myself a little bit when choosing the final project topic for my Applied Data Analysis class (you can view that on my GitHub). However, there were many flaws in the outcome, such as poor ROCs, ignoring seasons, no maps, and too many records being wiped out, etc., making the prediction less accurate.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">美本新生生存指南</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/collection/2023/05/06/advice.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="美本新生生存指南" /><published>2023-05-06T00:53:10-05:00</published><updated>2023-05-06T00:53:10-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/collection/2023/05/06/advice</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/collection/2023/05/06/advice.html"><![CDATA[<h3>出行篇</h3>

<ol>
  <li>可申请加拿大旅游签证，有效期直到你护照过期前一天。</li>
  <li>别从欧洲转机了，屁股疼。</li>
  <li>(此条适用于中部同学在美国国内出行)可以试着将目的地或出发的设置为学校本地机场。例如前往芝加哥ORD国际机场，可以考虑American Airlines，从学校所在城市出发。因为AA具有较多的1小时左右的短途航班，可以让你往返于ORD与学校所在城市的本地机场。</li>
  <li>不要带太多行李。烧水壶、泡面锅之类的没必要，一有亚马逊，二有Temu或AliExpress，三来这类小家电很有可能不适应110V（手机、电脑等等倒是不用担心）。冬季衣物可以寄过来，也可以在当地买。被子床单一概没必要，本地都有。</li>
  <li>大部分电子产品并不需要变压器，可以适应110~240V电压。电脑充电器，可以提前在国内电商下单美标脚插，把适配器上的脚插换掉就好了。</li>
  <li>国产安卓、华为不支持谷歌框架。手机国外买去吧。苹果倒是出国了能用，但到美国如果买新苹果电子产品，还能用学生身份打折（反之如果在大陆返校季购买，非大陆学生可能无法认证并享受折扣）。</li>
  <li>苹果手机用户，出国了请换区。</li>
  <li>请尽早拿到手机卡。漫游的网络因为还是走国内运营商，不支持谷歌、YouTube。</li>
  <li>美国手机卡，流量先试试5个G一个月，够用，因为流量相比国内溜得没那么严重。再说校园Wifi覆盖的。</li>
</ol>

<h3>休闲娱乐篇</h3>

<ol>
  <li>听音乐可以抛弃掉国内软件了。不想花钱的可以用Spotify，除了播几首歌会插播广告。不想要广告的请使用Apple Music或Spotify Premium.</li>
  <li>如果你是Windows用户，GitHub上有个叫Spot++的东西。</li>
  <li>买一切软件、会员之前，看看有无学生折扣。</li>
  <li>喜欢使用论坛的，可以使用Reddit或Quora。</li>
  <li>想省钱的，GitHub搜索Spot++。</li>
</ol>

<h3>学习篇</h3>

<ol>
  <li>（重要）请向大学递送你的AP/IB/A-Level成绩，可以帮你免掉部分通识课。就算不能免专业课学分，这些学分可以让你早于别人选课（重要）！！早于别人选宿舍！！</li>
  <li>学校Writing Center是个有用的地方，帮忙润色作文，甚至能帮忙Brain Storm。</li>
  <li>请看看你的Degree Audit是否Waive掉了你的二外要求。如果没有，请尽早联系Registrar Office.</li>
  <li>建议第一个学期先上专业课，因为（1）你的AP学分可能要一段时间后才能到学校，有些课你不需要上，但是到达之前学校还没有更新degree audit。（2）有些课可以同时满足两个gen ed category。如果你还不熟悉degree audit，不知道第二学期会开什么课，先别选gen ed。（3）不少通识课有May Term或暑课。</li>
  <li>很多Gen Ed可以去Community College上，价格不贵，还Asynchonous。</li>
  <li>可以参考一个网站：rate my professors。不一定准确，但可以参考。同时问一下你的同学。</li>
  <li>部分学校有非专业的 music scholarship, audition通过，可以waive掉乐器私教课的费用。课程是算Applied Minor，也就是给minor 学生上的课。授课的教授一般同时给音乐系上课，水平很高，也很善于点拨，强调用耳朵听音色（这点比教业余钢琴的做得好太多），而不是蛮练。</li>
  <li>如果大学前的数学为你留下了negative impression，那么（个人观点）我夸张一点讲：大学之前的数学都不算数学，以前的东西（尤其是初中数学），八股文而已。如果你不反感STEM，实际不一定反感数学，只是反感以前的老师。</li>
  <li>非常建议上一门历史课，重点不在于背史料，而在于辨析一个作者是否包含预设的立场及bias。</li>
</ol>

<h3>生活篇</h3>

<ol>
  <li>Meal Plan多半用不完。</li>
  <li>部分学校单人间很难住进去，除非有medical condition。ADHD也算。</li>
  <li>你的AP/IB/A-Level学分可以可以让你住更好的房子。例如你有8门AP的情况下，算8门课的credit（不论是否抵掉专业课），进来就算Sophmore而不是Freshman。等个一年，变成Junior的时候，就可以住进Junior才能住的房子了，普遍条件更好。</li>
  <li>校园卡可能让交通费免费。</li>
  <li>Amazon Prime, 学生6个月免费，但是这六个月不包含Amazon Music和有声书。</li>
  <li>Rate My Professors网站上可以参考学校的治安状况、食物水平等等。</li>
  <li>Dollar Tree的东西便宜。</li>
  <li>Walgreens、CVS 可以打疫苗。同时一些国内昂贵的疫苗，例如HPV疫苗等等，包含在你的medical insurance里面（insurance贵啊），免费。建议出国打。</li>
  <li>啥衣物，洗衣机洗就完事了，反正外国同学也是啥衣服都往机子里丢。最好将深浅色衣物颜色分开。一，你读书没时间。二，当代年轻人手洗水平堪忧。三，机洗洗得比手洗干净。买个洗衣篮，往里放，一周跑一趟洗衣房。</li>
  <li>纯棉衣物等等，请低温洗涤。</li>
  <li>国外使用烘干机而非室外晾衣。烘干的时候加点柔顺烘干纸(Fabric Softener)，店里都有。</li>
  <li>外卖可以Uber送。</li>
  <li>（重要）强烈建议拥有一本驾照。在美国，没车寸步难行，尤其是你就读于村校、文理学院这种。当然，如果你在大城市，还是步行或公共交通吧，例如纽约没车位的。不过呢，如果没有驾照，也不用太焦虑。找个会开车的同学就OK了，再不济公交线路也是有的。</li>
  <li>学校直饮水机很多，一般为凉水。虽然本人不喝热水，但需要热水的，食堂、咖啡馆里应该有。毕竟外国人也有不少冲茶包的。</li>
  <li>办个本地银行卡，这样付学费就能少付一些第三方手续费。学校一般会组织办卡的。</li>
  <li>学校有收发快递的点。</li>
</ol>

<h3>交友篇</h3>

<ol>
  <li>找一个社团，有助于认识本地人及国际生。ACM、IEEE、交响乐团、合唱团之类的比较推荐，或者如果弹钢琴，被拉去钢琴伴奏也不错。</li>
  <li>不管是哪里人，大家都是人。人类之间的共性超乎你想象。</li>
  <li>多和本地人聊之后英语会变好。</li>
  <li>常用App: Whats App/Telegram/Instagram/Discord/SnapChat。</li>
  <li>It can be hard to find local friends if there’s no chance. It’s fine. 很多时候，也需要契机。</li>
  <li>你可以选择与哪些朋友一块儿。这是你的自由。你有权利接受与拒绝。</li>
  <li>没有人有理由威胁你远离你的朋友。如遇到，请寻求学校或当地帮助。</li>
</ol>

<h3>反思与展望篇</h3>

<ol>
  <li>历史是任人打扮的花姑娘。请多看看不同渠道的信息。</li>
  <li>对民粹主义保持警惕，无论在哪里，无论发起人来自于自己国家还是你的所在地。</li>
  <li>在对新闻、历史发表看法前，从多国媒体、书籍了解事情的前因后果，再发表议论。</li>
  <li>We might be more stubbon than we thought to be.</li>
  <li>You are not alone. 你不是一个人。</li>
  <li>尊重自己及他人说话的权利。</li>
  <li>对自己预设的立场保持警惕，并在讨论中反思。</li>
  <li>若有证据，你有权利反驳。</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Collection" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[出行篇]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">对初中教育的一些看法</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/random/thoughts/2023/03/19/%E5%AF%B9%E5%88%9D%E4%B8%AD%E6%95%99%E8%82%B2%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E4%BA%9B%E7%9C%8B%E6%B3%95.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="对初中教育的一些看法" /><published>2023-03-19T00:53:10-05:00</published><updated>2023-03-19T00:53:10-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/random/thoughts/2023/03/19/%E5%AF%B9%E5%88%9D%E4%B8%AD%E6%95%99%E8%82%B2%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E4%BA%9B%E7%9C%8B%E6%B3%95</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/random/thoughts/2023/03/19/%E5%AF%B9%E5%88%9D%E4%B8%AD%E6%95%99%E8%82%B2%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E4%BA%9B%E7%9C%8B%E6%B3%95.html"><![CDATA[<p>这篇文章与我的英文Blog里面不同。英文blog里主要谈到了对数学科目的看法。这篇文章更侧重于非一线/准一线至二线城市的初中可能存在的问题。</p>
<p>我并不希望读者去扒我的初中及教师，因为我想这或许不只是一个学校存在的issue。而且，教师的行为很可能是无意识的（此处并非洗白）。</p>
<p>我的初中班主任曾经推出过一个叫“学习管理本”的东西。一天中午，所有人拿到了一本簿子，封皮厚实，我以为是学校的一种鼓励（感觉是学习忙，班级给的礼品）。班主任在投影仪上放出了一份手写列表，大致是：</p>
<p>---------------</p>
<p>XX:00 起床</p>
<p>XX:10-XX:20 吃饭</p>
<p>XX:10-XX:00 英语听力（详细文字我已经忘记了）</p>
<p>XX:XX-XX:XX XXXX</p>
<p>...</p>
<p>11:00 睡觉</p>
<p>---------------</p>
<p>一份学习及睡觉列表巨细无遗。不过不得不承认，这可以说是一个初中三好学生的范本，那种平常人很难做到的案例。</p>
<p>班主任让我们把所有的作息、做过的事，全部写道这个学习管理本上。</p>
<p>一周、一个月…… 整个班级照做了。每周班主任会把反例投影到大屏幕上，作经验交流，并点评一翻。几个学霸刷题到挺晚，有个挺上进的学生，班主任也劝身体要紧。有个学神平常直接早早睡了（后来老师对他也是睁一只眼闭一只眼）。比较惨的是当年动作慢的几个，比如我和我前排的一哥们儿（高中大学也挺有思想的一个人），数据看起来不如别人漂亮。没有老师会妥协减作业的，睡得晚，那肯定是“动作慢”，你的问题。</p>
<p>渐渐地我觉得这个“学习管理本”太烦，还把我的生活暴露在外。以后我就写几行，再后来干脆不交了，感觉没意思。</p>
<p>2018年某一天，可能由于“管理本”交的人少了，班主任有所察觉，有点气，就让所有人站起来，盘查，详细内容忘了，问为什么没写。其他同学如实说了，保证继续写。学神早就不记录了，觉得没有必要（他有自己安排的一套），班主任也无所谓，让他坐下了，同学们惊叹了一下，但也服气。</p>
<p>轮到我了，我直接表明，“我不想写”。</p>
<p>"为什么？"班主任流露出了一种海关拷问可疑人员的神情。</p>
<p>“我觉得没意思。” 我当时已经有些恍惚了。</p>
<p>我直接和班主任僵了几秒钟，所有人注视着我。多数人在想什么，我不知道，毕竟我不会读心术，但场面是凝固的，气氛类似于：</p>
<p>你一个平平无奇的家伙也配？</p>
<p>估计认为耗着也没意思，班主任看了一眼：“坐下吧。”</p>
<p>从此我再也没有交过管理本。</p>
<p>后来从班主任那边知道，这管理本的前身是计划本，原先是一栏计划，一栏实际操作的时间表，原先是给某个更厉害的中学用的，到我们这儿“简化”了。但是，真正的精华是安排一个可行的计划（我想不是定一个超额而苛刻的时间表，要求100%完成），对自己有个评估并，逐渐调整适合自己的进度，并逐渐提高上限。但是，巨细无遗的作息审视并不应该是精华。它的主人公是学生吗？</p>
<p>今天又想起这学习管理本，心里一惊：这不就是"Big Brother Is Watching You"吗？</p>
<p>同时，这个管理本，有没有可能是暗中支持造假的体现呢？一份漂亮的数据，被远远看重于学生的实际能力，尤其是几个动作慢的学生。事实上，上文提到的我前排的哥们，是一个注重理解知识的人，不是那种作业看似写得很快却一点都不会举一反三的人。</p>
<p>我仍然记得，另一位教师曾发过一份关于作业量及作息的问卷，最终的调查结果是作业量大、不少学生都晚睡。然而调查结果非但没有换来作业量的减少或优化（有些机械性重复的作业完全没必要，例如数学、科学作业本第一板块的填空），该教师还看起来不悦，并谴责我们动作慢。</p>
<p>对于一个无法诚实面对客观现实、不优化教育方式的人，以及它背后的教育体系，我感到担忧。</p>
<p>可惜教师、家长、学生，多是一种社会的产物。越无意识，越接近社会培养出的。</p>
<p>我校的生源并不算差。家长强调，这学校好啊，生源好，学生人也不错。其它一些学校，可能类似于泥腿子社会，甚至一些地方存在地痞流氓。但是我校更像是《1984》那种（表面）秩序但窒息的社会。如果有人问我，如果再回到从前，你怎么选，我会摇摇头，表示这个问题没有意义。1984似乎更文明，相比野蛮社会，极端情况下有秩序或许好于无秩序，但以地痞流氓的标准来衬托1984的“优越性”，实在是有些可笑了。我并非赞同泥腿子社会，但是我不认为两者之一是最优解。</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Random" /><category term="Thoughts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[这篇文章与我的英文Blog里面不同。英文blog里主要谈到了对数学科目的看法。这篇文章更侧重于非一线/准一线至二线城市的初中可能存在的问题。 我并不希望读者去扒我的初中及教师，因为我想这或许不只是一个学校存在的issue。而且，教师的行为很可能是无意识的（此处并非洗白）。 我的初中班主任曾经推出过一个叫“学习管理本”的东西。一天中午，所有人拿到了一本簿子，封皮厚实，我以为是学校的一种鼓励（感觉是学习忙，班级给的礼品）。班主任在投影仪上放出了一份手写列表，大致是： --------------- XX:00 起床 XX:10-XX:20 吃饭 XX:10-XX:00 英语听力（详细文字我已经忘记了） XX:XX-XX:XX XXXX ... 11:00 睡觉 --------------- 一份学习及睡觉列表巨细无遗。不过不得不承认，这可以说是一个初中三好学生的范本，那种平常人很难做到的案例。 班主任让我们把所有的作息、做过的事，全部写道这个学习管理本上。 一周、一个月…… 整个班级照做了。每周班主任会把反例投影到大屏幕上，作经验交流，并点评一翻。几个学霸刷题到挺晚，有个挺上进的学生，班主任也劝身体要紧。有个学神平常直接早早睡了（后来老师对他也是睁一只眼闭一只眼）。比较惨的是当年动作慢的几个，比如我和我前排的一哥们儿（高中大学也挺有思想的一个人），数据看起来不如别人漂亮。没有老师会妥协减作业的，睡得晚，那肯定是“动作慢”，你的问题。 渐渐地我觉得这个“学习管理本”太烦，还把我的生活暴露在外。以后我就写几行，再后来干脆不交了，感觉没意思。 2018年某一天，可能由于“管理本”交的人少了，班主任有所察觉，有点气，就让所有人站起来，盘查，详细内容忘了，问为什么没写。其他同学如实说了，保证继续写。学神早就不记录了，觉得没有必要（他有自己安排的一套），班主任也无所谓，让他坐下了，同学们惊叹了一下，但也服气。 轮到我了，我直接表明，“我不想写”。 "为什么？"班主任流露出了一种海关拷问可疑人员的神情。 “我觉得没意思。” 我当时已经有些恍惚了。 我直接和班主任僵了几秒钟，所有人注视着我。多数人在想什么，我不知道，毕竟我不会读心术，但场面是凝固的，气氛类似于： 你一个平平无奇的家伙也配？ 估计认为耗着也没意思，班主任看了一眼：“坐下吧。” 从此我再也没有交过管理本。 后来从班主任那边知道，这管理本的前身是计划本，原先是一栏计划，一栏实际操作的时间表，原先是给某个更厉害的中学用的，到我们这儿“简化”了。但是，真正的精华是安排一个可行的计划（我想不是定一个超额而苛刻的时间表，要求100%完成），对自己有个评估并，逐渐调整适合自己的进度，并逐渐提高上限。但是，巨细无遗的作息审视并不应该是精华。它的主人公是学生吗？ 今天又想起这学习管理本，心里一惊：这不就是"Big Brother Is Watching You"吗？ 同时，这个管理本，有没有可能是暗中支持造假的体现呢？一份漂亮的数据，被远远看重于学生的实际能力，尤其是几个动作慢的学生。事实上，上文提到的我前排的哥们，是一个注重理解知识的人，不是那种作业看似写得很快却一点都不会举一反三的人。 我仍然记得，另一位教师曾发过一份关于作业量及作息的问卷，最终的调查结果是作业量大、不少学生都晚睡。然而调查结果非但没有换来作业量的减少或优化（有些机械性重复的作业完全没必要，例如数学、科学作业本第一板块的填空），该教师还看起来不悦，并谴责我们动作慢。 对于一个无法诚实面对客观现实、不优化教育方式的人，以及它背后的教育体系，我感到担忧。 可惜教师、家长、学生，多是一种社会的产物。越无意识，越接近社会培养出的。 我校的生源并不算差。家长强调，这学校好啊，生源好，学生人也不错。其它一些学校，可能类似于泥腿子社会，甚至一些地方存在地痞流氓。但是我校更像是《1984》那种（表面）秩序但窒息的社会。如果有人问我，如果再回到从前，你怎么选，我会摇摇头，表示这个问题没有意义。1984似乎更文明，相比野蛮社会，极端情况下有秩序或许好于无秩序，但以地痞流氓的标准来衬托1984的“优越性”，实在是有些可笑了。我并非赞同泥腿子社会，但是我不认为两者之一是最优解。]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">对初中教育的一些看法</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/random/thoughts/2023/02/14/Some-Thoughts-About-Math.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="对初中教育的一些看法" /><published>2023-02-14T23:53:10-06:00</published><updated>2023-02-14T23:53:10-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/random/thoughts/2023/02/14/Some-Thoughts-About-Math</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/random/thoughts/2023/02/14/Some-Thoughts-About-Math.html"><![CDATA[<p>This is my first English blog article. Probably there are some grammatical errors, and thanks for your patience. </p>

<p>Recently I am reading [A Mathematician's Lament], a discussion about problems of traditional k12 math education. I was touched. The fisrt half of the book helped organize and speak out what I doubted about my junior high school math.</p>

<p>Below is my story. Math was the worst subject I performed in my junior high school. The exams were usually about geometry. All I had to do was to add guidelines and prove a claim like "showing (angle) XXX is 45 degrees". Possible lines burst out of my mind, but not all of them would work, and I it was impossible to try all of them at school. Homework was a lot, and exam time was limited. Being afraid of my math teacher to announce “time is up”, I struggled with questions uncompleted. Junior high school geometry turned to be my anxiety.</p>

<p>"Which guidelines should be added here? And why?" The exams were like gambling. If I made a guess and failed to work it out, time lost. Gradually, I did not dare to walk out my first step for proof. And I was confused in class, that why the teacher added guidelines in a fixed way, and how did my classmates come up with the "standard" solution. 

<p>All the anxiety accumulated. In 2018, when the mock graduation test ended, I was afraid of my math teacher saying, "if you done this question wrong, stand up", and giving a criticism. I asked my mother to text the teacher that I would be absent the next day. She agreed, and the teacher permitted.</p>

<p>Nobody told me why making guidelines in a specific way. All I heard was "this is a xxx model, so add like that", but why? Until in 2020, my senior high school friend told me, "I came up with xxx because this dot (pointing at the center of the circle) looked strange". Well, it was not a perfect explination for me because I don't understand how to define "strange", but at least it was a reason.</p>

<p>Another nightmare was calculation. I made lots of calculations mistakes in high schools. My senior high school teacher was confused about that, but one thing he mentioned (when having discussion with my mother) was, "math is intuition". I did not fully understand that in 2021, but later I realized a little bit, which I will talk about later. And in my opinion, "intuition" also means math is not supposed to be a calculation tool.</p>

<p>In 2023, I met a nice professor teaching "Logic, Sets, and Proof" in college. I chose this class and found him treating math as an art and philosophy. While taking this course, I was reading [Logic: A Very Short Introduction], whose idea inspired me that proof is using a clear way to persuade others in a reasonable way. Or in another word, it's the ability to explain ideas. </p>

<p>My thoughts about mathematical proof may not be perfect, but I feel relieved. I remember at the first or second day of lectures, my professor was doing proof, writing "there exists ... such that" (in my opinion "such that" is similar as "which allows") and paused. I can't recall if he introduced the philosophy idea of existence, but "existence" was something that he emphasized. At that time, I made an idea connection. "Which came first: chicken or the egg" flew my mind, and suddenly I gasped. Proof is the representation of the world! It's a philosophy! Damm! (When I was writing this blog, this scene triggers my senior high school school mate, whose favorite slogan was (printed on the school advertisement), "existence precedes essence" by Jean-Paul Sartre. Probably it was not talking about math, but I am amazed by it.) </p>

<p>After that lecture, the word "intuition" wirls in my mind, but I cannot explain it clearly. Intuition of Domino (this was my math professor's explination about induction)? Or the intuition of solving a problem (the road between claim and conclusion)? Or the intuition of finding a road between the starting point and the destination？I am not sure(lol). But my confidence is gradually back.</p>

<p>I have finished my story telling, and let us go back to the book. My conclusion is, math is not just a tool, and it should not be recitation. For me, junior high school tests were not "math", as it discouraged students spend time to think about possible approaches and try their ideas. It is fine to fail with some roads, but like art, no one rules a fixed solution as long as other ways also work out. Though preciseness is important, before that, creativity is essential.</p>

<p>Today when my group wrote down "loves(x,y)", the professor talked with us. "We need to define 'loves'... （can't remember）We need to make sure it's x loves y, not reversible" (ahh, a sad story (lol)), he beamed, "It's quite Valentine's Day, right?"</p>
</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Random" /><category term="Thoughts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is my first English blog article. Probably there are some grammatical errors, and thanks for your patience.]]></summary></entry></feed>